<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jupyter on Allen&#39;s Whiteboard</title>
    <link>https://allenfrostline.com/tags/jupyter/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jupyter on Allen&#39;s Whiteboard</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Allen Wang © 2016 - 2022</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 20:44:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://allenfrostline.com/tags/jupyter/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Adding a Python 2.7 Kernel in Jupyter</title>
      <link>https://allenfrostline.com/blog/py27-kernel/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 20:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://allenfrostline.com/blog/py27-kernel/</guid>
      <description>It can be tricky when someone asks you to use Python 2.7 in a jupyter notebook nowadays, but not impossible:
Up-to-Date Anaconda Before we start installing anything, let&amp;rsquo;s update anaconda.
conda update conda In case of error concerning setuptools, you may reinstall it before the update. In that case, the scripts would be
conda uninstall setuptools conda install setuptools conda update --force conda Python 2.7 Environment We need, of course, a brand new python 2.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bad Interpreter Error of Jupyter and its Solution</title>
      <link>https://allenfrostline.com/blog/bad-interpreter-error-jupyter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 14:56:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://allenfrostline.com/blog/bad-interpreter-error-jupyter/</guid>
      <description>I always wanna clean up my dev environment thoroughly, once for good. After all these years messing up with virtualenv, conda, pip as well as all the other languages than Python: R, Java, Node.js, Julia, Golang&amp;hellip; My computer finally started going nuts. Jupyter notebook threw me the following error every time I start it:
zsh: /usr/local/bin/jupyter: bad interpreter: /usr/local/opt/python/bin/python3.7: no such file or directory It turns out that the cause was that along with reinstallation of Python, the homebrew symlinks to Jupyter are now broken.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Run Jupyter Notebook within Virtualenv</title>
      <link>https://allenfrostline.com/blog/jupyter-virtualenv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2018 00:55:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://allenfrostline.com/blog/jupyter-virtualenv/</guid>
      <description> # create virtualenv myenv mkvirtualenv myenv # enter virtualenv workon myenv # install jupyter if it&amp;#39;s not done yet (myenv) pip3 install jupyter # install ipykernel if it&amp;#39;s not done yet (myenv) pip3 install ipykernel # create new kernel of python3 (myenv) python3 -m ipykernel install --user --name myenv --display-name &amp;#34;Python 3&amp;#34; # start the notebook within myenv (myenv) jupyter notebook </description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
