<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>cryptocurrency on Allen&#39;s Whiteboard</title>
    <link>https://allenfrostline.com/tags/cryptocurrency/</link>
    <description>Recent content in cryptocurrency on Allen&#39;s Whiteboard</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2019 11:04:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://allenfrostline.com/tags/cryptocurrency/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid Sentiment-Momentum Strategy in Cryptocurrency Market</title>
      <link>https://allenfrostline.com/blog/crypto-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2019 11:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://allenfrostline.com/blog/crypto-news/</guid>
      <description>This is an exploratory research trying to implement a simple yet robust sentiment analysis mechanism in the cryptocurrency market. We call it a hybrid sentiment-momentum strategy as it applies context analysis (or more specifically, word analysis) into traditional momentum strategies and adjusts position automatically over time using both factors. The hybrid strategy is implemented with backtesing period from Dec. 17th 2017 to May 2nd 2019. It yields cumulative return of 229% and a remarkable Sharpe ratio of 2.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cryptocurrency Arbitrage (3): One More Strategy</title>
      <link>https://allenfrostline.com/blog/cryptocurrency-arbitrage-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2018 16:04:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://allenfrostline.com/blog/cryptocurrency-arbitrage-3/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been months since my last update on cryptocurrency arbitrage strategies. The original version has been completely driven off the market and thus I decided to develop a new one. The market is primitive and savage in many senses, by which I mean there&amp;rsquo;re supposed to be a bunch of inefficiency and corresponding arbitrage opportunities.
On the top of the page is the backtest PnL of the new strategy 4 from Jan 1 up to yesterday, July 26.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cryptocurrency Arbitrage (2): Performance</title>
      <link>https://allenfrostline.com/blog/cryptocurrency-arbitrage-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 02:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://allenfrostline.com/blog/cryptocurrency-arbitrage-2/</guid>
      <description>Below is the PnL plot of the multi-coin arb strategy. The strategy is running on Amazon EC2 and portfolio value pulled dynamically to plot this using plotly. Timezone is set at my local time, i.e. Europe/Amsterdam. Cheers!
Update April 11:
Strategy offline before I realized my AWS bills was being owed and the server down due to that&amp;hellip; Performance excl. and incl. loss due to holding costs and enforcing execution, etc.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cryptocurrency Arbitrage (1): Some Ideas</title>
      <link>https://allenfrostline.com/blog/cryptocurrency-arbitrage-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2017 19:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://allenfrostline.com/blog/cryptocurrency-arbitrage-1/</guid>
      <description>Coinbase has just launched BCH as an alternative to BTC because of the high transaction fees and annoying delays of the latter one. As a result, the exchange rate of USD/BCH rocketed tenfolds within 24 hours. Together with BTC, mainstream altcoins like ETH and ETC faced significant slump since a week ago. On contrary, XRP, because of the rumored endorcement from big companies like Amazon, is experiencing a straight appreciation of almost 100% since two weeks ago.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
